The other day I had to log into a service I hadn’t used before.
前几天，我得登录一项以前没用过的服务。
Since I was a new user, the website decided that it needed to check I wasn’t a robot and so set me a Captcha test to determine whether the user is a person or a machine.
由于我是新用户，网站认定需要核实我不是机器人，于是给我出了一道验证码测试题，以确定用户是人还是机器。
I was presented with an image of a roadside scene over which was laid a grid.
呈现在我面前的是一张路边场景的图片，图上铺着一层网格。
My “challenge” was to click on each cell in the grid that contained a traffic sign.
我的“挑战”是点击网格中每一个含有交通标志的格子。
I did so, a bit irritated.
我照做了，心里有点恼火。
Then I was presented with another image and another grid—also with a request to identify road signs.
接着，呈现在我面前的又是一张图片和一个网格，同样要求我识别出道路标志。
Like a lamb, I complied, after which the website accepted my input.
我像羔羊一样乖乖照办，随后网站接受了我输入的信息。
And then I realised what I had been doing was adding to a dataset for training the machine-learning software that guides self-driving cars.
这时我才意识到，我刚才一直在做的，是扩充一个数据集，这个数据集用于训练引导自动驾驶汽车的机器学习软件。
So, to gain access to an automated service that will benefit financially from my input, I first have to do some unpaid labor to help improve the performance of autonomous vehicles.
所以，一项自动化服务将从我输入的信息中获得经济利益，而我为了获准使用它，首先得做一些无偿劳动，帮助提升自动驾驶车辆的性能。
Neat, eh?
挺巧妙的，是吧？
But note also the delicious additional irony that the Captcha is described as an “automated Turing test”.
不过还要注意另一层绝妙的讽刺：验证码被称作“自动化图灵测试”。
The Turing test was conceived, you may recall, as a way of enabling humans to determine whether a machine could respond in such a way that one couldn’t tell whether it was a human or a robot.
你也许还记得，图灵测试当初被构想为一种方法，使人类能够判断一台机器能否回应得让人分辨不出它是人还是机器人。
So we have wandered into a world in which machines make us do tricks to prove that we are humans!
这么说来，我们已经不知不觉走进了这样一个世界：机器让我们表演把戏，来证明自己是人类！
The strangest aspect of this unparalleled shift is how under-discussed it has been.
这一前所未有的转变最奇怪的地方，在于人们对它的讨论一直如此之少。
The metaphor of the boiling frog comes to mind.
我脑海中浮现出“温水煮青蛙”这个比喻。
Have we become so subtly conditioned by digital technology that we don’t see what’s been happening to us?
数字技术是否已经如此潜移默化地驯化了我们，以至于我们察觉不到自己身上一直在发生什么？
Have we been conditioned to accept a world governed by “smart” tech, trading for convenience to the point where we become a bit like machines ourselves?
我们是否已经被驯化得接受了一个由“智能”技术主宰的世界，为换取便利而付出代价，以至于自己都变得有点像机器了？
In a recent startling and thoughtful book, two scholars—Brett Frischmann, a law professor, and Evan Selinger, a philosopher—argue that the answer to that question is “yes”.
在最近一本令人震惊又见解深刻的书中，两位学者——法学教授布雷特·弗里施曼和哲学家埃文·塞林格——认为，这个问题的答案是肯定的。
And they’re right.
他们说得没错。
There’s nothing technophobic about that.
这么说丝毫没有技术恐惧的意味。
We shape our tools and then our tools shape us.
我们塑造工具，然后工具又塑造我们。
Technology is supposed to provide tools that serve human ends.
技术本应提供工具，服务于人类的目的。
But, as the machine-learning Captcha demonstrates, a significant proportion of digital tech now sees (and uses) humans as means to ends that are not ours.
但正如这个用于机器学习的验证码所表明的，如今相当一部分数字技术把人类视为（并用作）手段，去实现并非我们自己的目的。
In the process, it reduces us to the status of cheery rats running on treadmills designed by people who do not have our interests at heart.
在此过程中，这些技术使我们沦为在踏车上欢快奔跑的老鼠，而设计这些踏车的人并不把我们的利益放在心上。
So back to the frog metaphor.
那么，再回到温水煮青蛙这个比喻上来。
Are we smart enough to jump out before it’s too late?
我们是否足够聪明，能趁还来得及跳出来？
You don’t even have to Google it to know the answer.
你甚至不用上谷歌搜一下，就知道答案。